MAXIM SHOLONIK

Frontend developer



- Belarus, Brest (ready to relocate or work remotely)
- +375 (33) 674-14-14
- makcsholonik@gmail.com









ABOUT ME

I am a person who has a strong passion for programming. I have experience in with React, Redux, creating SPA TypeScript. Now I am improving my skills in this direction and expanding them withnew technologies. I spend my leisure time on Codewars or with educational books. Open for your suggestions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Freelance Sep. 2021 - present

- -Taking part in creating learning app, developed login page, modal windows, tests, menu, and design;
- -Using next developer technologies: React, Redux, ReduxThunk, RestAPI, Axios, Formik, MaterialUI, etc;
- -Migration to Typescript;
- -Work with Hooks;
- -Performance enhancement (memo, useCallback, lazy, Suspense etc.);
- -Checking the correctness of the code with Unit Tests, applying Storybook fordemonstration of individual modules of the application.

SALES MANAGER PP Polesie JV, Ltd. Oct. 2016 - Jan. 2022

- -Working with a client base, searching and attracting new clients:
- -Control of receivables:
- -Participation in exhibitions:
- -Tracking and analyzing sales statistics based on key quantitative metrics;
- -Assisting the management team with analytics and decisions:
- -Objectives setting, coaching performance monitoring of merchandisers.

EDUCATION

FRONTEND DEVELOPER (React + Redux, TS) IT-incubator.by 2020 - 2021

ECONOMIST

Belorussian trade-economic university of consumer cooperation 2010 - 2015

SKILLS

- React
- Redux
- TypeScript
- REST API
- Unit tests
- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- English (Beginner)
- Russian (Native)